Their debut match has begun.
開始了呢，出道戰
Vice-Captain Hoshina! I found the core!
保科副隊長，我找到核心的位置了
-What? -It's at the base of the neck.
-什麼？ -在頸部的底部
And another thing. This is more important.
還有一點，這很重要
The yoju have reproductive organs, too.
餘獸也有增殖器官
If we don't destroy these,
不破壞的話，餘獸的屍體
more yoju might be born from the dead bodies.
搞不好會生出新的餘獸
Target captured. No shooting attack target in the area.
目標鎖定 周邊不存在對狙擊手的威脅對象
Roger. Begin shooting now.
瞭解，開始射擊
Watch carefully, Kafka.
看清楚了
This is… the power of the person you're working to stand next to.
這就是…你想要並肩之人的力量
Honju has been destroyed! All movements have stopped.
主獸已摧毀，徹底停止活動
Just as expected.
不出所料
Even with the honju dead,
就算解決掉主獸
the remaining yoju left in its dead body
屍體中殘留的餘獸
will flood out at the end.
最後會一湧而出
Hey, you didn't hear the alert?
喂，你沒聽到警報嗎？
Cleanup will be done later.
還不到解體業者進來的時候
Him, too.
這傢伙也一樣
The reproductive organ I placed has been destroyed.
埋進去的增殖器官被破壞了
Is there an officer with extensive kaiju knowledge?
隊員裡是不是有很瞭解怪獸的人啊？
Damn!
天啊
That honju's huge!
主獸好大隻
-Are Kafka and Ichikawa there? -There's no way I can see them!
-卡夫卡和市川也在嗎？ -怎麼可能看得到？
It makes sense that all cleaners in Tokyo and Kanagawa were summoned for this.
難怪會把東京和 神奈川的解體業者全部找來
Hey.
喂
-You guys see the newbie? -What?
-有看到新人嗎？ -咦？
He's probably locked himself in the bathroom again.
他是不是又去蹲廁所了啊？
-Should I go call for him? -Yeah, please do.
-我去叫他吧？ -麻煩你了
Hey, you. This area's still dangerous.
喂，我說你，這邊還很危險
Wait until there are instructions…
在收到指示前乖乖等著
Run, Iharu-kun!
伊春，快躲開！
Dang, I missed his heart.
啊，沒打中心臟
My accuracy isn't as good in this form.
這個姿態打不準啊
Iharu-kun!
伊春！
-It won't stop bleeding, shit! -Calm down!
-血流個不停 -冷靜下來
Control the bleeding.
先進行止血操作
What the hell are you?
你是什麼鬼東西？
A kaiju?
怪獸？
A humanoid kaiju who's not Senpai? That means…
前輩以外的人型怪獸，那不就是…
The humanoid kaiju that appeared at the exam arena!
在測驗會場出現的人型怪獸
He's the one that got Shinomiya?
就是他嗎？打敗四之宮的傢伙
Most likely.
應該沒錯
Well, it'd be a waste to retreat now.
唉，就這樣撤退也不太好
Maybe I'll get some live samples of some officers.
至少抓幾個隊員回去當活體樣本好了
Platoon Leader Ikaruga! We've encountered a humanoid kaiju. Please provide backup.
斑鳩小隊長，我們遇到人型怪獸 請立刻派人支援…
Platoon Leader!
小隊長！
-No way! -Sure, sure.
-怎麼會？ -沒錯
Wireless communication, right? I already dealt with that.
通訊器嘛，那個已經攻略完畢了
We're in an area that can't be detected by the outside.
這一帶現在處於 外界無法感知的空間中
It was originally used to sneak into the human world.
原本是用來藏身人類世界的技術
But it's useful for hunting, too.
沒想到也能用來狩獵呢
Reno!
雷諾！
Huh?
奇怪？
I keep missing my aim.
都會微妙地偏移目標呢
It penetrates the suit shield easily.
他的攻擊能輕易穿透戰鬥服的護盾
But…
不過…
Oh, I see.
喔，你啊
You can see it, right?
你看得到對吧？
Right. I'll let you know in case you encounter him.
對了，以防你們遇到那傢伙 先告訴你們一件事
It looks like magic or a spell at first,
雖然乍看下像魔法或妖術
but watch his fingers.
但仔細看他的指尖
There's a pattern to his movements.
他會有一定的準備動作
I can dodge it!
我能躲開！
He dodged it!
他躲掉了！
I knew it.
果然沒錯
Iharu-kun, leave and call for backup.
伊春，快撤退去呼叫支援
Why do I have to be protected by you?
為什麼搞得像你在保護我的…
-Ow! -Iharu-kun!
-好痛！ -伊春
Please go.
請你…快走吧
I'm afraid.
好可怕
He even got Shinomiya.
能打倒四之宮的對手
There's no way I could beat him.
我怎麼可能有勝算？
But the officer I want to be is…
但我想成為的隊員…
Run, Ichikawa!
市川，快跑！
Once you're in a safe area, make a report.
到了安全的地方就通知防衛隊
…a man who can risk his life
…是在這種時候
for his friends at a time like this!
會為了同伴挺身而出的男人！
I can at least buy enough time for Iharu-kun to call for backup.
至少要爭取時間讓伊春能夠撤退
Reno's completely different from the way he was yesterday.
雷諾的動作跟昨天明顯不一樣
What the hell? How is he able to fight a thing like that?
搞什麼？ 為什麼他能跟那種傢伙戰鬥？
Shit!
可惡…
I hate him!
真不爽…
There's a barrier to unleashed combat power.
解放戰力有分界線存在
It's around 20% to 30%.
大約會在20%到30%出現
Only a few people can get over that barrier.
能跨過那條界線的人少之又少
But everyone has the potential to be that person.
不過，每個人都有跨越的可能性
I haven't gotten past 20% for over two weeks now.
我已經停在20%快兩個星期了
Ever since that day,
從那天開始
I've only thought about how to be strong.
我活著只想著要變強
But…
但是…
He outran me so easily.
那傢伙竟然輕易地超越我
I hate him!
看他真不爽啊！
Sounds like you had information about me beforehand.
你啊，似乎事先就知道我的情報
But you don't know this, do you?
這個就不知道了吧？
Huh?
哎呀？
Iharu-kun? Why…
伊春？為什麼…
That's not it. It's not Reno I hate.
不對，我不爽的不是雷諾
It's the guy who hasn't changed a bit since that day.
是從那天之後就沒有任何長進
The guy who's always being protected. It's me!
只會接受別人保護的自己
Listen up, Reno.
聽好，雷諾
You're not the one protecting me.
不是你來保護我
I'm the one protecting you, dumbass!
是我來保護你才對，大笨蛋
Iharu-kun!
伊春！
Can't understand them one bit.
無法理解
-I thought you were calling for help. -Shut up.
-我以為你去求救了 -吵死了
If I didn't come back, you would've been killed.
要是我沒回來，你早就被幹掉了
I see. He was trying to let him escape.
啊，原來是想逃跑啊？
What a waste.
沒用的
Nothing and no one can leave this area without my permission.
無論是物品或生物 沒有我的許可，就無法離開這裡
You hear that?
聽到了吧？
We just have to take our chances.
我們只能拼了
Let's crush that thing together, Reno!
一起幹掉那傢伙吧，雷諾！
But I'm in this state.
不過我傷成這樣
I'll be your backup and distract him.
只能掩護你，替你製造機會
Crush him with your best shot!
你就用最大火力一槍把他轟飛
Yes!
好！
Let's go, Reno!
上吧，雷諾！
A conductor round?
雷擊彈？
Don't think you're the only one
在嘗試不同子彈的人
trying out different bullets!
可不是只有你而已！
It's hard to move around with this.
這東西讓我行動不方便
Maybe I'll stop him first.
先解決那邊好了
Watch carefully.
仔細觀察
I took it once. I know the timing now.
吃了一記攻擊，多少也能掌握時機了
This one, too?
這邊也是啊？
Now, Reno!
就是現在，雷諾！
Combat Power, Maximum Release!
戰力最大限度解放！
Please, God. Just this once.
神啊，求求你，只有現在就好
Just for this moment, please give me power
在這個瞬間賜給我…
that's stronger than Shinomiya or Captain Ashiro.
勝過四之宮和亞白隊長的力量
Please!
拜託了！
What the hell?!
什…麼？
A wall of dead bodies?
屍體堆成的牆？
Looks like you've exhausted
看你的樣子
all your options now, huh?
應該是無計可施了吧？
Reno!
雷諾！
Vice-Captain Hoshina. This is Platoon Leader Ikaruga.
保科副隊長，這裡是斑鳩小隊
What's up?
怎麼了？
I've lost contact
我從剛才
with Officers Ichikawa and Furuhashi for a while now.
就連絡不上市川和古橋兩名隊員
What?
你說什麼？
We cannot detect any wireless network vitals at all!
這裡也完全偵測不到兩人的生命跡象
Ichikawa?
市川嗎？
Did that move for a second?
剛剛那是不是動了一下？
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡
Kikoru! This signal, does this mean…
琪歌露，這個反應是…
Yeah. He's here.
嗯，那傢伙來了
Ichikawa, Iharu!
市川、伊春！
Reno!
雷諾！
My body is hot all over.
身體好熱
Stop the bleeding and stand up. I'm still alive.
得快進行止血站起來，我還活著
The fighting isn't over.
戰鬥還沒結束
You're still moving?
你還能動啊？
It's harder than I thought
要殺死活著以外的功能
to stop all functions while keeping them alive.
沒想到挺難的啊
Like I'd let you do that!
別想得逞！
I'm tired of that already.
那個我已經習慣了
All right. Let's finish this one up.
好了，差不多該解決這邊這個了
Is this too weak?
這樣太輕了嗎？
-Shit! -It still moves. How's this?
-可惡 -還能動嗎？那這樣呢？
My friend's being hurt in front of me,
同伴在面前被打得遍體鱗傷
and I can't do anything?
我卻什麼辦法也沒有
It pisses me off,
我不甘心
and I don't want to admit it,
我不想承認
but Reno's a super strong guy.
但是雷諾真的很厲害
I know he's going to be Captain one day.
他以後一定會當上隊長
I won't let his life end here!
我怎麼能讓他死在這裡？
This one is nice and ready,
這邊已經處理好了
so, I don't need you any more.
已經不需要你了
Please, God.
神啊，求求你
I don't care if it's a demon or a devil. Please…
不對，不管是惡鬼還是惡魔都好
Please help Reno.
救救雷諾…
Please help…
救救我的…
my friend.
朋友吧
You can die now.
你可以去死了
You're the one that's dying, you bastard!
要死的是你這混帳！
What just happened?
發生什麼事了？
I can see my body.
我能看見我的身體
I see. He decapitated me.
啊，我的頭被打飛了啊
Sorry for being late.
抱歉，我來晚了
I'm so weak.
我太弱了
I tried so hard
還以為能夠獨自解決
so it wouldn't come to this.
不會落到這種下場
But even then,
但結果還是…
I made him transform again.
讓這個人變身了
Another humanoid?
另一隻人型怪獸？
You must be that.
你就是那個吧？
The much rumored
傳聞中的…
Kaiju No. 8.
怪獸8號
Sorry, Ichikawa. It might take a bit longer.
抱歉啊，市川，看來還要花點時間
It'll be okay. Calm down.
沒事的，不要緊張
Stop the bleeding one by one, using your suit.
一個一個仔細地幫傷口止血吧
I don't have to teach you that!
是說這輪不到我來教吧？
I don't know how.
我又不會用
Senpai, be careful.
前輩，小心點
Yeah. Leave it to me.
我知道，交給我吧
I know that Senpai's strong.
我知道前輩很強
But I have a bad feeling about this.
但我有不好的預感
It's fine, but you're a kaiju.
我是無所謂啦
Why do you get in my way?
但你明明是怪獸，為什麼要妨礙我？
And you're a much stronger kaiju than I thought.
而且你這怪獸比我想得要強很多呢
I'd love to have your dead body as my chess piece.
好想用你的屍體當棋子
He injured Senpai in his kaiju form?
竟然能傷到怪獸型態的前輩？
I see. You're tough.
原來如此，很堅固呢
In order to kill you…
要殺死你的話…
will this be enough?
至少需要拿出這種力量
That kaiju…
這傢伙…
He wasn't trying at all with us!
跟我們戰鬥時完全沒用全力
-Run, Senpai! -I see.
-前輩，快逃… -這樣啊
You shot this thing in their bodies
你就是用這種攻擊在他們身上
over and over?
開了好幾個洞吧？
Huh?
咦？
What's going on?
為什麼？
The wall of dead bodies!
屍體的牆壁！
I'll take this time to reconstruct.
趁機修復傷口…
What?
什麼？
What's with him? Protect the body. Avoid a direct hit.
這傢伙怎麼搞的？防守、躲開直擊…
He's beating me? This isn't normal.
被壓制了？好奇怪
Something's wrong.
情況不對勁
I don't have time to reconstruct the damage.
受傷的地方修復得很慢
Confusion. Retreat for now.
混亂，暫時撤退
Don't have time to retreat.
找不到撤退的時機
The core is in the body, right?
核心在軀幹裡吧？
I'm blowing you away, so brace yourself.
我現在就打穿，給我咬緊牙關！
This isn't good.
這下完蛋了
The core got exposed completely.
核心徹底露出來了
It's over.
你玩完了
This is Platoon Leader Ikaruga.
這裡是斑鳩小隊
We've discovered a humanoid kaiju!
發現了人型怪獸
There's not enough power.
威力不夠
Where did he go?
那傢伙跑到哪裡去了？
You're going to find Reno and Iharu?
你要去找雷諾和伊春？
We lost communication with them, and we can't sense their vitals.
聯絡不上又偵測不到生命跡象
So, how…
你要怎麼找？
If they're with the humanoid from before…
如果那隻人型怪獸在他們旁邊…
NEUTRALIZATION BUREAU
（討伐廳）
…I'd be able to sense them.
…我應該能感覺得到
Kikoru! I leave this area to you.
琪歌露，這邊就交給你了
Hey!
等一下！
Transforming in a place like this?
竟然在這種地方變身
This is Platoon Leader Ikaruga!
這裡是斑鳩小隊
We've spotted a humanoid kaiju in District Foxtrot,
在F地區東南區域
Southeast Area!
發現人型怪獸！
Physical traits match those of Kaiju No. 8.
根據特徵判斷，應該是怪獸8號
Roger. We'll send a neutralization unit right away.
瞭解，我馬上派討伐部隊過去
That idiot!
那個笨蛋
The mimetic space broke, huh?
擬態空間壞掉了嗎？
But thanks to that…
不過多虧如此
you got distracted.
讓我找到機會脫身了
Shit!
糟糕！
I understand your traits now. Next time, I can kill you.
我已經掌握你的特徵了 下次就會殺了你
I won't let you escape!
別想跑！
You act like a human, even though you're a kaiju.
你明明是怪獸，做的事卻像人類
Let's meet again, Kaiju No. 8.
後會有期，怪獸8號
Shit! There's nothing I can do. I have to leave now, too.
可惡，沒辦法了，我也快逃吧
-He got away! -Let's rescue the injured officers.
-他逃走了 -快救受傷的隊員
I'm glad. I let the humanoid escape,
太好了，雖然讓人型怪獸跑了
but I achieved my goal.
但至少達成目的了
A pitch black body and a demon-like skull mask.
漆黑的肉體，形似惡鬼的骷髏面具
I finally caught your tail,
終於逮到你的尾巴了
Kaiju No. 8.
怪獸8號
Vice-Captain Hoshina?
保科副隊長？
This is Hoshina. I'm in District Foxtrot.
我是保科，在F地區
I've made contact with Kaiju No. 8.
與怪獸8號接觸
So, you've met my officers, huh?
我們的隊員似乎受到你不少照顧呢
No, Vice-Captain Hoshina.
不對，保科副隊長
That is…
那個人是…
I'm better at the small and mid-sized kaiju than her.
要是對付中小型怪獸 應該是我更勝一籌
He wasn't lying.
他不是在虛張聲勢
He's well-experienced at fighting small kaiju.
他很擅長跟小型怪獸戰鬥
His skin is so tough!
還真硬
I'm sure I got two or three cuts in.
我明明砍中了兩、三下
I've only seen him smiling and friendly.
之前只看過他嘻皮笑臉的樣子
But this is…
但這就是…
Looks like I have to get serious.
看來我得拿出真本事了
…what Vice-Captain Hoshina looks like when he's about to kill a kaiju.
要殺死怪獸時的保科副隊長
Applying for permission to release the limiter control.
申請解除限制
Roger.
瞭解
I'll take care of No. 8.
8號就由我…
Unleashed combat power, 92%.
解放戰力92%
I'll neutralize him.
…來討伐
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻譯：唐詠傑